Papers from the Jim Walsh Collection
Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress
- Series 8. Bound Publications, 1901-1977, and undated, 14 linear feet
  This series consists of bound journals, columns, pamphlets, and a diary. Many of the publications in the series include Walsh’s notes and handwritten indices.
  Arranged alphabetically by description or title.
  The publications have been placed unboxed on shelves, adjacent to the boxed portion of the Walsh papers.
  - The Columbia Record, 1904-1907, 1 volume.
    Includes Walsh’s notes.
  - "Dave Garraway’s Today Program, Thursday, May 15, 1958," 1958
    Bound scrapbook of photographs, clippings, and correspondence documenting Walsh’s appearance on the television show.
  - Jim Walsh diary, 1977
    Handwritten. Consists mostly of personal notes and includes a few clippings and photographs.
  - "Edison and Pathé Pamphlets," undated
    Miscellaneous pamphlets bound together.
  - Edison Diamond Points (1915-1917) bound with Phonographianna (1956) and Along Broadway (1917-1922), 1915-1922, 1956
  - Edison Phonograph Monthly and Edison Amberola Monthly, 1903-1921, 13 volumes.
  - "Edison Tone Test Clippings / Victor Cut-Out Lists," 1915-1917, and undated
    Clippings and theater illustrations mounted on heavy cardstock and housed in a large pamphlet box.
  - "Elide Morris: Her Life and Letters," 1961-1971
    Bound scrapbook of correspondence, photographs, articles, and copies of clippings, dated 1910-1914.
  - "Favorite Pioneer Recording Artists," 1942-1975, 15 volumes.
    Walsh’s Hobbies columns, some with additional notes and miscellaneous items.
  - "Jim Walsh in Hobbies," 1935-1974, 3 volumes.
    Photocopies of Jim Walsh’s Hobbies columns.
  - "Magazine Articles by and about Jim Walsh," 1929-1969
    Bound scrapbook of newspaper and magazine clippings.
  - Numerical List of Victor Records, 1912, 1914-1915
  - "Phonograph Advertising: Literary Digest and Other Magazines," 1902-1931, and undated
    Scrapbook of advertisements from magazines and newspapers.
  - "Pioneer Phonograph Advertising," 1901-1932, and undated
    Bound scrapbook of advertisements from magazines and newspapers.
  - Sound Wave and Talking Machine Record, 1909-1910
    Bound periodical.
  - Talking Machine News, 1903-1936, 20 volumes, bound.
  - Voice of the Victor, 1907-1926, 3 volumes.
    Includes notes.
  - "Woodymay Recording Company: Compendium," circa 1940-1948, and undated
    Bound scrapbook with Edison signature, collector signatures, letterhead, photographs, clippings, cards, and other illustrations.
Transferred Materials
A print of Charles Dickens, autographed by Dickens, was transferred to the Library of Congress Prints and Photographs Division in November, 2010. Several published books, bound journals, and record catalogs also were removed from the collection and integrated into the Library’s general collections.